<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:jalbum="http://jalbum.net/jalbumrss">
    <channel>
        <title>Clavariaceae - Рогатиковые - Coral Fungi - Korallenpilze</title>
   	<link>../../..</link>
        <generator>jAlbum 31.1</generator>
   		<description>The Clavariaceae, commonly known as Coral Fungi, is a diverse family of fungi within the Basidiomycota phylum. This family consists of approximately 30 genera and 500 species worldwide. The fungi in this family exhibit a variety of shapes and sizes, including coral-like branching structures, simple clubs, and more complex forms.

Coral fungi are characterized by their fruiting bodies (basidiocarps), which grow above ground and are typically composed of densely packed, elongated branches. The fruiting bodies can range in size from less than 1 cm to over 20 cm in height.

The color of these fungi varies widely, from white, yellow, and orange to pink, purple, and brown. Their texture is often brittle or waxy, and they usually grow on the ground or on decaying wood.

The spore-producing structures, known as basidia, are found lining the surfaces of the branches. Spores are typically smooth, hyaline (transparent), and vary in size and shape depending on the species.

Coral fungi are saprotrophic, meaning they obtain nutrients by decomposing dead organic material. They play a crucial role in breaking down and recycling nutrients in forest ecosystems.

These fungi can be found in a wide range of habitats, from temperate to tropical forests, as well as grasslands and other environments where decaying plant material is present.

Some species of Clavariaceae are edible and appreciated for their unique appearance and texture. However, many species are not recommended for consumption due to their tough or bitter taste.

It is essential to exercise caution when foraging for edible coral fungi, as some species may resemble toxic or inedible mushrooms.

Coral fungi can be challenging to identify to the species level, as many of them have similar appearances. Microscopic examination and molecular techniques are often required for accurate identification.

The study of Clavariaceae has led to the discovery of unique compounds with potential pharmacological applications, such as antibacterial and antifungal properties.</description>
        <jalbum:absolutePath>https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Clavariaceae/</jalbum:absolutePath>
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Clavariaceae/%D0%9A%D0%BB%D0%B0%D0%B2%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D1%8F%20%D0%B3%D0%BB%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B0%D1%8F%20-%20Clavaria%20argillacea/album.rss" title="Clavaria argillacea - Клавария глинистая - Clay Club Fungus - Tonfarbene Keule" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Clavariaceae/%D0%9A%D0%BB%D0%B0%D0%B2%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D1%8F%20%D0%B3%D0%BB%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B0%D1%8F%20-%20Clavaria%20argillacea/thumbs/DSC07034.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Clavariaceae/%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B6%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Clavulinopsis%20corniculata/album.rss" title="Clavulinopsis corniculata - Рогатик рожковидный - Meadow Coral - Hörnchen-Koralle" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Clavariaceae/%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B6%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Clavulinopsis%20corniculata/thumbs/DSC04064.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    </channel>
</rss>
