<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:jalbum="http://jalbum.net/jalbumrss">
    <channel>
        <title>Pluteaceae - Плютеевые - Pluteus Family - Dachpilzverwandte</title>
   	<link>../../..</link>
        <generator>jAlbum 31.1</generator>
   		<description>The Pluteaceae, also known as the Pluteus Family or Dachpilzverwandte, is a family of basidiomycete fungi within the order Agaricales. This family is relatively diverse, containing several genera, including Pluteus and Volvariella. Members of the Pluteaceae family are characterized by their free gills, pink spore prints, and the absence of a partial veil or cortina.

Pluteus cervinus, commonly known as the Deer Shield, is a widespread and well-known species within the Pluteaceae family. This mushroom has a convex to flat cap that ranges from 4 to 15 cm in diameter, with a light to dark brown coloration and a smooth, often slightly sticky surface.

The gills of Pluteus cervinus are free, meaning they do not attach to the stipe, and they have a pinkish hue due to the color of the spores. The stipe is typically 5 to 12 cm in height and 0.5 to 1.5 cm in thickness, with a white to pale brown color and a slightly fibrous texture.

Members of the Pluteaceae family can be found growing on various substrates, including dead wood, leaf litter, and rich soil. They are primarily saprobic, which means they decompose dead organic matter, playing an essential role in nutrient cycling within ecosystems.

The Pluteaceae family has a global distribution, with species found in North America, Europe, Asia, and other regions of the world. The fruiting period for these mushrooms generally occurs from late spring to autumn.

The spores of Pluteaceae species are typically smooth, elliptical, and pink in color. For example, the spores of Pluteus cervinus measure approximately 6 to 8 µm in length and 4 to 5 µm in width.

Some species within the Pluteaceae family are considered edible, such as Volvariella volvacea, commonly known as the Straw Mushroom. However, other species may be inedible or of poor culinary quality, so care should be taken when collecting these mushrooms for consumption.

The chemical composition of Pluteaceae species has not been extensively studied, but some research suggests they may contain bioactive compounds with potential medicinal properties, such as antioxidant and antimicrobial activities.</description>
        <jalbum:absolutePath>https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pluteaceae/</jalbum:absolutePath>
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pluteaceae/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B9%20%D0%BE%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B9%20-%20Pluteus%20cervinus/album.rss" title="Pluteus cervinus - Плютей олений - Deer Shield - Rehbrauner Dachpilz" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pluteaceae/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B9%20%D0%BE%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B9%20-%20Pluteus%20cervinus/thumbs/DSC03895.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pluteaceae/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B9%20%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D1%8F%20-%20Pluteus%20romellii/album.rss" title="Pluteus romellii - Плютей Ромелля - Romell&apos;s Pluteus - Romells Dachpilz" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pluteaceae/%D0%9F%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B9%20%D0%A0%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D1%8F%20-%20Pluteus%20romellii/thumbs/0SET08851.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    </channel>
</rss>
