<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:jalbum="http://jalbum.net/jalbumrss">
    <channel>
        <title>Helvellaceae - Гельвелловые - Helvellas - Lorcheln</title>
   	<link>../../..</link>
        <generator>jAlbum 31.1</generator>
   		<description>The Helvellaceae family, commonly referred to as helvellas or Lorcheln in German, is a group of fungi belonging to the order Pezizales. The family contains several genera, including Helvella, Gyromitra, and Rhizina, among others.

Fungi within the Helvellaceae family are characterized by their unique, often intricate fruiting bodies. These structures can be variously shaped, such as cup-like, saddle-like, or lobed, and are often found in shades of brown, black, or gray.

Helvellaceae fungi are predominantly found in the Northern Hemisphere, including North America, Europe, and Asia. They can be encountered in a variety of habitats, such as forests, grasslands, and disturbed areas, depending on the specific species.

Members of the Helvellaceae family often form ectomycorrhizal relationships with trees, especially conifers and hardwoods. This symbiotic association benefits both the fungus and the host tree by facilitating nutrient exchange.

Some species in the Helvellaceae family are considered edible, while others are toxic or inedible. It is essential to accurately identify these fungi to avoid potentially dangerous mistakes.

One well-known species within this family is Gyromitra esculenta, which is known to contain the toxin gyromitrin. Consumption of this species can lead to severe gastrointestinal distress, liver and kidney damage, and even death.

On the other hand, some species of Helvella, such as H. crispa and H. lacunosa, are considered edible when cooked, although their edibility remains a matter of debate among mycologists and foragers.

Spore morphology and size can vary within the Helvellaceae family, but they are generally elliptical, smooth, and colorless.

Members of the Helvellaceae family have been used traditionally for various medicinal purposes, although scientific research supporting these uses is limited.

Fruiting bodies of Helvellaceae fungi typically appear during spring and fall, depending on the species and local environmental conditions.

The taxonomy of the Helvellaceae family has undergone numerous revisions, with molecular studies providing new insights into the relationships between genera and species.

Some Helvellaceae fungi demonstrate potential for use in bioremediation, as they can accumulate heavy metals and other contaminants from their environment.

In recent years, researchers have been investigating the potential of Helvellaceae fungi as sources of bioactive compounds for pharmaceutical and industrial applications.

Conservation efforts are essential to protect the habitats and ecosystems supporting Helvellaceae fungi, as many species are sensitive to environmental changes and human disturbance.</description>
        <jalbum:absolutePath>https://fungarium.netlify.app/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Pezizomycetes/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pezizales/%D0%93%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Helvellaceae/</jalbum:absolutePath>
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.netlify.app/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Pezizomycetes/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pezizales/%D0%93%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Helvellaceae/%D0%9B%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%B1%D0%BE%D0%BA%D0%B0%D0%BB%D1%8C%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Helvella%20acetabulum/album.rss" title="Helvella acetabulum - Лопастник бокальчатый - Vinegar Cup - Essigbecher-Helmling" thumbnail="https://fungarium.netlify.app/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Pezizomycetes/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pezizales/%D0%93%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Helvellaceae/%D0%9B%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%B1%D0%BE%D0%BA%D0%B0%D0%BB%D1%8C%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Helvella%20acetabulum/thumbs/0SET09003.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.netlify.app/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Pezizomycetes/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pezizales/%D0%93%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Helvellaceae/%D0%9B%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%B1%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B7%D0%B4%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Helvella%20lacunosa/album.rss" title="Helvella lacunosa - Лопастник бороздчатый - Fluted Black Elfin Saddle - Gefurchter Lerchensporn" thumbnail="https://fungarium.netlify.app/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Pezizomycetes/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pezizales/%D0%93%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Helvellaceae/%D0%9B%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%B1%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B7%D0%B4%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Helvella%20lacunosa/thumbs/fungi-0004148.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.netlify.app/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Pezizomycetes/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pezizales/%D0%93%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Helvellaceae/%D0%9B%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%BA%D1%83%D1%80%D1%87%D0%B0%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Helvella%20crispa/album.rss" title="Helvella crispa - Лопастник курчавый - White Saddle Fungus - Krause Lerchensporn" thumbnail="https://fungarium.netlify.app/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Pezizomycetes/%D0%9F%D0%B5%D1%86%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Pezizales/%D0%93%D0%B5%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Helvellaceae/%D0%9B%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%BA%D1%83%D1%80%D1%87%D0%B0%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Helvella%20crispa/thumbs/DSC03621.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    </channel>
</rss>
