<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:jalbum="http://jalbum.net/jalbumrss">
    <channel>
        <title>Crepidotaceae - Крепидотовые - Crepidotaceae family - Schüpplinge</title>
   	<link>../../..</link>
        <generator>jAlbum 31.1</generator>
   		<description>The Crepidotaceae is a family of basidiomycete fungi that belong to the order Agaricales. This family is known for its diverse range of gilled mushrooms, many of which exhibit a characteristic scaly appearance on their caps.

Members of the Crepidotaceae family usually have brown spores and gills that are attached to the stem or free from it. The fruiting bodies generally have a central stipe and a cap that is often covered with scales or fibrils.

Crepidotaceae fungi can be found in various habitats, such as forests, grasslands, and other terrestrial environments. Many species are saprotrophic, meaning they decompose dead organic matter, particularly wood.

These fungi are distributed worldwide and can be found in regions such as North America, Europe, Asia, and Australia.

The Crepidotaceae family includes several genera, such as Crepidotus, Simocybe, and Phaeomarasmius.

Crepidotaceae fungi play a vital role in their ecosystems, as they help break down and recycle organic matter, contributing to nutrient cycling and soil fertility.

The spore sizes and shapes in Crepidotaceae are variable, with most species producing smooth, ellipsoid, or subglobose spores. Spore print colors can range from brown to rusty-brown or dark brown.

Many Crepidotaceae species exhibit a range of odors and tastes, which can aid in identification. For example, some species may have a mild or earthy odor, while others may have a distinctive radish-like smell.

None of the species within the Crepidotaceae family are considered to be choice edibles, and many are inedible or have unknown edibility.

Although there are no deadly toxic species in this family, consuming inedible or unidentified mushrooms can still lead to gastrointestinal distress and other symptoms.

Crepidotaceae fungi are not generally known for their medicinal properties, but further research may reveal potential applications in this area.

Due to the ongoing advancements in molecular phylogenetics, the taxonomic classification of Crepidotaceae is subject to change, and some genera or species may be reclassified in the future.

Identifying Crepidotaceae fungi can be challenging due to their morphological similarities with other brown-spored mushrooms. Accurate identification often requires the examination of microscopic features and the use of chemical tests.</description>
        <jalbum:absolutePath>https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Crepidotaceae/</jalbum:absolutePath>
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Crepidotaceae/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%20%D0%B8%D0%B7%D0%BC%D0%B5%D0%BD%D1%87%D0%B8%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Crepidotus%20variabilis/album.rss" title="Crepidotus variabilis - Крепидот переменчивый - Variable Oysterling - Variabler Zärtling" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Crepidotaceae/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%20%D0%B8%D0%B7%D0%BC%D0%B5%D0%BD%D1%87%D0%B8%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Crepidotus%20variabilis/thumbs/DSC07870.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Crepidotaceae/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%20%D0%BC%D1%8F%D0%B3%D0%BA%D0%B8%D0%B9%20-%20Crepidotus%20mollis/album.rss" title="Crepidotus mollis - Крепидот мягкий - Soft Crepidotus - Weicher Schwindling" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Crepidotaceae/%D0%9A%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B4%D0%BE%D1%82%20%D0%BC%D1%8F%D0%B3%D0%BA%D0%B8%D0%B9%20-%20Crepidotus%20mollis/thumbs/DSC06440.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    </channel>
</rss>
