<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:jalbum="http://jalbum.net/jalbumrss">
    <channel>
        <title>Cyphellaceae - Цифелловые - Cyphella Family - Cyphella Familie</title>
   	<link>../../..</link>
        <generator>jAlbum 31.1</generator>
   		<description>The Cyphellaceae family is a group of fungi belonging to the order Agaricales, characterized by their distinct fruiting bodies called cyphellae. These cyphellae are small, cup- or disc-shaped structures that form on the surface of wood, bark, or other substrates.

Members of the Cyphellaceae family typically have white, cream, or pale-colored spores, which are produced on the inner surface of the cup- or disc-shaped fruiting body. The spore-producing structure, known as the hymenium, is smooth, wrinkled, or even tooth-like in some species.

These fungi are saprotrophic, meaning they obtain nutrients by decomposing dead organic matter. They play an essential role in breaking down wood and other plant materials, contributing to nutrient cycling within their ecosystems.

Cyphellaceae species can be found worldwide, with a higher diversity in tropical and subtropical regions. They are particularly common in rainforests, where they can be found on decaying logs, branches, and other plant debris.

The size of the fruiting bodies in Cyphellaceae species can vary greatly, with some being less than a millimeter in diameter, while others can reach several centimeters.

Many Cyphellaceae species are inconspicuous, often being overlooked due to their small size and growth on substrates like bark or decaying wood.

The taxonomy of the Cyphellaceae family is still not fully resolved, with ongoing research uncovering new species and genera.

Some Cyphellaceae species are known to form associations with algae or cyanobacteria, resulting in lichenized fungi. These lichenized species play crucial roles in their ecosystems as primary producers and nutrient cyclers.

The fruiting bodies of some Cyphellaceae species are also known to be used as shelter by small invertebrates, like mites and springtails, contributing to the complex ecological interactions within their habitats.

Some well-known genera within the Cyphellaceae family include Cyphella, Porodisculus, and Merismodes.

The genus Cyphella is the type genus of the family and is characterized by small, cup- or disc-shaped fruiting bodies with a smooth or slightly wrinkled hymenium.

The genus Porodisculus is known for its disc- or cushion-shaped fruiting bodies and a hymenium with a tooth-like appearance.

The genus Merismodes is characterized by its small, cup-shaped fruiting bodies, which are often found on decaying wood in tropical and subtropical forests.</description>
        <jalbum:absolutePath>https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A6%D0%B8%D1%84%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Cyphellaceae/</jalbum:absolutePath>
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A6%D0%B8%D1%84%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Cyphellaceae/%D0%A5%D0%B5%D0%B9%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%84%D0%B8%D0%BB%D0%BB%D1%83%D0%BC%20%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%B9%D1%88%D0%B8%D0%B9%20-%20Cheimonophyllum%20candidissimum/album.rss" title="Cheimonophyllum candidissimum - Хеймонофиллум белейший - White Oysterette - Weißer Austernpilzähnlicher" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A6%D0%B8%D1%84%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Cyphellaceae/%D0%A5%D0%B5%D0%B9%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%84%D0%B8%D0%BB%D0%BB%D1%83%D0%BC%20%D0%B1%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%B9%D1%88%D0%B8%D0%B9%20-%20Cheimonophyllum%20candidissimum/thumbs/fungi-0001527.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A6%D0%B8%D1%84%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Cyphellaceae/%D0%A5%D0%BE%D0%BD%D0%B4%D1%80%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B5%D1%80%D0%B5%D1%83%D0%BC%20%D0%BF%D1%83%D1%80%D0%BF%D1%83%D1%80%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Chondrostereum%20purpureum/album.rss" title="Chondrostereum purpureum - Хондростереум пурпурный - Silverleaf fungus - Violetter Schichtpilz" thumbnail="https://fungarium.info/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B%20-%20Agaricomycetes/%D0%90%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Agaricales/%D0%A6%D0%B8%D1%84%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Cyphellaceae/%D0%A5%D0%BE%D0%BD%D0%B4%D1%80%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B5%D1%80%D0%B5%D1%83%D0%BC%20%D0%BF%D1%83%D1%80%D0%BF%D1%83%D1%80%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B9%20-%20Chondrostereum%20purpureum/thumbs/DSC06715.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    </channel>
</rss>
